Eswara Srinivas Lanka

Full Stack Developer

Phone: 8867458799

Address: Bangalore, India

Email: eswarasrinivaslanka@gmail.com

A Full Stack Web Developer with 8 years of experience having an In-depth understanding of web technologies and Backend technologies . Involved in design, planning, and implementation of various Web & Mobile applications using open source technologies.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, Html, Css, JavaScript, TypeScript.

Frameworks/Tools: Spring boot, Nodejs, Angular, React, Redux, Bootstrap, Git, Junit, Karma, Jasmine, Jest.

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.

Others: Agile Development, Test Driven Development.

EXPERIENCE

Monsanto March 2016 to Present

Senior Software Developer

- Responsible for design & architecture.
- Agile development and Test driven development.
- Backend API development using Spring Boot MicroServices, JAVA, Hibernate, Node js, Maven.
- Web Apps development using Angular PWA, React and Redux frameworks.
- Familiar with Unit testing frameworks Junit, Karma, Jasmine, Jest.
- Familiar with using github, jenkins and ci/cd tools.
- Familiar with SQL/Mongo DB.
- Was Involved in Hiring Talents.

Projects implemented using JAVA, Angular and React are:

- Incubator.
- It-toolbox.
- Pipeline Mass Update.

TATA ELXSI LTD.

December 2010 to March 2016

Software Developer

- Front end development using HTML, CSS & Javascript.
- Api development using Spring rest framework/JAVA.
- Involved in Design and Development.
- Worked on HAVI for Television applications.
- Worked on Selenium grids, XML parser, db4o database.
- Familiar with SQL/Mongo DB
- Migration from JAVA 4 to JAVA 7.

Many Projects were implemented using JAVA/HAVI, MONGO DB and Restful Services. Some of them are:

- InfoSID Processor.
- ADR US and International
- Profile Generator.

EDUCATION

JNTU KAKINADA UNIVERSITY

2006-2010

Bachelors of Technology(Computer Science & Engineering)